# Shubham Gulati

Software Engineer - Certified Cloud Architect - 6+ Years Experience - B.Tech & M.Tech in C.S.E.

Toronto, ON - linkedin.com/in/iamshgulati - shubhamgulati.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Shubham is an award-winning Software Engineer with over 6 years of experience at top U.S. and Canadian consulting firms. He has a Master's degree in CSE, certifications in AWS, and specializations in Cloud Computing, and Application Security. He excels at building scalable enterprise solutions using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices. And apart from his strong experience in backend technologies, he also has a good understanding of frontend technologies, making him well-suited for full-stack software development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Deloitte** India

Senior Consultant Jun 2022 - Nov 2022

- Led a backend team to enhance the client's usage reporting application, resulting in a 25% improvement in user satisfaction.
- Promoted software engineering best practices, leading to 35% increase in reliability and adherence to high quality standards.
- Conducted training sessions and code reviews for new hires in the team, improving the team's onboarding efficiency by 20%.
- Actively participated in sprint planning with key stakeholders, ensuring timely reporting and successful delivery of the project.

**Deloitte** India

Consultant Sep 2019 - May 2022

- Architected and developed personalized features for a client's Customer Support Portal, increasing user satisfaction by 25%.
- Developed a reusable foundation for all Microservices, enhancing the system reliability and reducing technical debt by 30%.
- Integrated a Spring Cloud Config Server and HashiCorp Vault for easy management of secrets, reducing security risk by 40%.
- Resolved performance bottlenecks, improving the performance and scalability of critical features like search and downloads.

**Deloitte** India

# **Business Technology Analyst**

Apr 2018 - Aug 2019

- Transformed complex HR Portal monolith with 750+ APIs to cloud-native Microservices, improving system scalability by 35%.
- Developed resilient Microservices using Java, Spring Boot, and Spring Cloud, resulting in scalable and maintainable backend.
- Delivered high precision modules like Mergers & Acquisitions and Career Advancement, enhancing system reliability by 20%.
- Delivered well-organized API collections and OpenAPI endpoints to QA and Support teams, reducing transition time by 50%.

CGI Inc

# **Associate Software Engineer**

Aug 2016 - Apr 2018

- Developed RESTful web services with comprehensive unit tests for a client's call and data billing platform for M2M IoT devices.
- Developed innovative framework to manage state of production system using JMX, reducing maintenance downtime by 95%.
- Transformed applications from Oracle WebLogic Server to embedded Tomcat Server with Spring Boot, reducing license costs.

#### **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

**AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate**, Amazon Web Services (AWS) **AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner**, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5
JJMV6422RJ1Q1NWV

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS**

Backend: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Lombok; JUnit, Power Mockito; Node.js; RESTful APIs, Web Services, OpenAPI; Microservices, Event-driven Architecture, Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ; JDBC, JPA, Hibernate. Database: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL; NoSQL, MongoDB. Frontend: React.js, JavaScript, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS, Next.js. Package Managers: Maven, Gradle, NPM, PNPM. Cloud: AWS (including EC2, Lambda, ALB, API Gateway, RDS, DynamoDB, S3, CloudFormation), GCP, Infrastructure as Code. Orchestration: Docker, Jenkins, GitHub Actions. Tools: Postman; Git, GitHub; SonarQube; VSCode, IntelliJ IDEA, WebStorm; Jira, Agile/ Scrum. Security: HashiCorp Vault, OAuth, JWT; SSH, TLS, CAP, AAA; Software Supply Chain.

2017

## **EDUCATION**

Postgradua	ate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga College, Waterloo, ON	2024
Postgradua	ate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan Polytechnic, Saskatoon, SK	2023
Master of T	echnology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, India	2015
Bachelor o	f Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, India	2014
HONOURS & AWARDS		
Conestoga	- President's Honour List Award, Top of the merit list in Computer Application Security program.	2024
Conestoga	- High Distinction Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Computer Application Security program.	2024
Conestoga	- Best of Program Award, Best Capstone Project in Computer Application Security program.	2024
Saskpoly	– Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Cloud Computing & Blockchain program.	2023
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project.</li> </ul>	2022
Deloitte	- Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project.	2020
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project.</li> </ul>	2019
Deloitte	- Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project.	2019
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Spot Award, Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live.</li> </ul>	2019
Deloitte	<ul> <li>Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development.</li> </ul>	2018

## **PROJECTS**

CGI

Blog - Built a personal website/blog using React, Typescript, and Next.js, with a CI/CD pipeline using GitHub Actions.

 Contributed to software supply chain security of open-source OSCAR project used in Canadian Healthcare industry. OSCAR EMR

- Built a full-stack journaling platform using AWS serverless services, and fully automated CI/CD pipeline. **Emoverse** 

Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project.

SmartDegree - Built a DApp to issue digital certificates using Solidity and Web3 and deployed on Ethereum blockchain.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

## Research Paper

- An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System.
- Published in the IEEE Journal https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723